<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <commands>
		<command>
			<name>fcrackzip</name>
			<params>
				<param>File</param>
				<type>file</type>
			</params>
			<options>
				<option>
					<name>h</name>
					<aliases>
						<alias>help</alias>
					</aliases>
					Prints the version number and (hopefully) some helpful insights.
				</option>
				<option>
					<name>v</name>
					<aliases>
						<alias>verbose</alias>
					</aliases>
					Each -v makes the program more verbose.
				</option>
				
      <command>
         <name>Gzip</name>
         <options>
            <option>
               <name>a</name>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>ascii</alias>
               </aliases>
              Ascii text mode: convert end-of-lines using  local  conventions.
              This  option  is  supported  only  on some non-Unix systems. For
              MSDOS, CR LF is converted to LF when compressing, and LF is con‐
              verted to CR LF when decompressing.
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>c</name>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>stdout</alias>
                  <alias>to-stdout</alias>
               </aliases>
               Write  output on standard output; keep original files unchanged.
              If there are several input  files,  the  output  consists  of  a
              sequence  of  independently compressed members. To obtain better
              compression, concatenate  all  input  files  before  compressing
              them.
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>d</name>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>decompress</alias>
                  <alias>uncompress</alias>
               </aliases>
               Decompress.
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>f</name>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>force</alias>
               </aliases>
              Force compression or decompression even if the file has multiple
              links or the corresponding file already exists, or if  the  com‐
              pressed data is read from or written to a terminal. If the input
              data is not in a format recognized by gzip, and  if  the  option
              --stdout  is  also  given, copy the input data without change to
              the standard output: let zcat behave  as  cat.   If  -f  is  not
              given,  and  when not running in the background, gzip prompts to
              verify whether an existing file should be overwritten.
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>h</name>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>help</alias>
               </aliases>
               Display a help screen and quit.
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>l</name>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>list</alias>
               </aliases>
                For each compressed file, list the following fields:

                  compressed size: size of the compressed file
                  uncompressed size: size of the uncompressed file
                  ratio: compression ratio (0.0% if unknown)
                  uncompressed_name: name of the uncompressed file

              The uncompressed size is given as -1 for files not in gzip  for‐
              mat,  such  as compressed .Z files. To get the uncompressed size
              for such a file, you can use:

                  zcat file.Z | wc -c

              In combination with the --verbose option, the  following  fields
              are also displayed:

                  method: compression method
                  crc: the 32-bit CRC of the uncompressed data
                  date and time: time stamp for the uncompressed file

              The  compression  methods  currently supported are deflate, com‐
              press, lzh (SCO compress -H) and pack.   The  crc  is  given  as
              ffffffff for a file not in gzip format.

              With  --name,  the  uncompressed name,  date and time  are those
              stored within the compress file if present.

              With --verbose, the size totals and compression  ratio  for  all
              files  is  also  displayed,  unless some sizes are unknown. With
              --quiet, the title and totals lines are not displayed.
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>L</name>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>license</alias>
               </aliases>
               Display the gzip license and quit.
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>n</name>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>no-name</alias>
               </aliases>
               When compressing, do not save the original file  name  and  time
              stamp by default. (The original name is always saved if the name
              had to be truncated.) When decompressing,  do  not  restore  the
              original  file name if present (remove only the gzip suffix from
              the compressed file name) and do not restore the  original  time
              stamp if present (copy it from the compressed file). This option
              is the default when decompressing.
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>N</name>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>name</alias>
               </aliases>
               When compressing, always save the original file  name  and  time
              stamp;  this  is  the  default.  When decompressing, restore the
              original file name and time stamp if  present.  This  option  is
              useful on systems which have a limit on file name length or when
              the time stamp has been lost after a file transfer.
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>q</name>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>quiet</alias>
               </aliases>
               Suppress all warnings.
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>r</name>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>recursive</alias>
               </aliases>
               Travel the directory structure recursively. If any of  the  file
              names  specified  on the command line are directories, gzip will
              descend into the directory and compress all the files  it  finds
              there (or decompress them in the case of gunzip ).
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>t</name>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>test</alias>
               </aliases>
               Test. Check the compressed file integrity.
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>v</name>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>verbose</alias>
               </aliases>
               Verbose. Display the name and percentage reduction for each file compressed or decompressed.
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>V</name>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>version</alias>
               </aliases>
               Version. Display the version number and compilation options then quit.
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>1</name>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>fast</alias>
               </aliases>
               Regulate the speed of compression using the specified  digit  #,
              where  -1  or  --fast  indicates  the fastest compression method
              (less compression) and -9 or --best indicates the  slowest  com‐
              pression  method  (best  compression).   The default compression
              level is -6 (that is, biased towards high compression at expense
              of speed).
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>2</name>
              Regulate the speed of compression using the specified  digit  #,
              where  -1  or  --fast  indicates  the fastest compression method
              (less compression) and -9 or --best indicates the  slowest  com‐
              pression  method  (best  compression).   The default compression
              level is -6 (that is, biased towards high compression at expense
              of speed).
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>3</name>
              Regulate the speed of compression using the specified  digit  #,
              where  -1  or  --fast  indicates  the fastest compression method
              (less compression) and -9 or --best indicates the  slowest  com‐
              pression  method  (best  compression).   The default compression
              level is -6 (that is, biased towards high compression at expense
              of speed).
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>4</name>
              Regulate the speed of compression using the specified  digit  #,
              where  -1  or  --fast  indicates  the fastest compression method
              (less compression) and -9 or --best indicates the  slowest  com‐
              pression  method  (best  compression).   The default compression
              level is -6 (that is, biased towards high compression at expense
              of speed).
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>5</name>
              Regulate the speed of compression using the specified  digit  #,
              where  -1  or  --fast  indicates  the fastest compression method
              (less compression) and -9 or --best indicates the  slowest  com‐
              pression  method  (best  compression).   The default compression
              level is -6 (that is, biased towards high compression at expense
              of speed).
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>6</name>
              Regulate the speed of compression using the specified  digit  #,
              where  -1  or  --fast  indicates  the fastest compression method
              (less compression) and -9 or --best indicates the  slowest  com‐
              pression  method  (best  compression).   The default compression
              level is -6 (that is, biased towards high compression at expense
              of speed).
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>7</name>
              Regulate the speed of compression using the specified  digit  #,
              where  -1  or  --fast  indicates  the fastest compression method
              (less compression) and -9 or --best indicates the  slowest  com‐
              pression  method  (best  compression).   The default compression
              level is -6 (that is, biased towards high compression at expense
              of speed).
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>8</name>
              Regulate the speed of compression using the specified  digit  #,
              where  -1  or  --fast  indicates  the fastest compression method
              (less compression) and -9 or --best indicates the  slowest  com‐
              pression  method  (best  compression).   The default compression
              level is -6 (that is, biased towards high compression at expense
              of speed).
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>9</name>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>best</alias>
               </aliases>
               Regulate the speed of compression using the specified  digit  #,
              where  -1  or  --fast  indicates  the fastest compression method
              (less compression) and -9 or --best indicates the  slowest  com‐
              pression  method  (best  compression).   The default compression
              level is -6 (that is, biased towards high compression at expense
              of speed).
            </option>
            <option>
               <name>S</name>
               <param>suffix</param>
               <aliases>
                  <alias>suffix</alias>
               </aliases>
               Use  suffix  .suf  instead  of .gz. Any suffix can be given, but
              suffixes other than .z and .gz should be avoided to avoid confu‐
              sion when files are transferred to other systems.  A null suffix
              forces gunzip to  try decompression on all given  files  regard‐
              less of suffix, as in:

                  gunzip -S "" *       (*.* for MSDOS)

              Previous  versions  of gzip used the .z suffix. This was changed
              to avoid a conflict with pack(1).
            </option>
         </options>
         <params>
            <param>
               <name>name1</name>
               <type>textfield</type>
            </param>
            <param>
               <name>name2</name>
               <type>file</type>
            </param>
            <param>
               <name>name3</name>
               <type>files</type>
            </param>
         </params>
         <description>
         Gzip  reduces  the  size  of the named files using Lempel-Ziv coding (LZ77).  Whenever possible, each file is replaced by one with the extension
       .gz, while keeping the same ownership modes, access and modification times.  (The default extension is -gz for VMS, z for MSDOS, OS/2 FAT,  Win‐
       dows  NT  FAT  and  Atari.)  If no files are specified, or if a file name is "-", the standard input is compressed to the standard output.  Gzip
       will only attempt to compress regular files.  In particular, it will ignore symbolic links.

       If the compressed file name is too long for its file system, gzip truncates it.  Gzip attempts to truncate only  the  parts  of  the  file  name
       longer  than  3 characters.  (A part is delimited by dots.) If the name consists of small parts only, the longest parts are truncated. For exam‐
       ple, if file names are limited to 14 characters, gzip.msdos.exe is compressed to gzi.msd.exe.gz.  Names are not truncated on  systems  which  do
       not have a limit on file name length.

       By  default,  gzip  keeps  the  original  file name and timestamp in the compressed file. These are used when decompressing the file with the -N
       option. This is useful when the compressed file name was truncated or when the time stamp was not preserved after a file transfer.

       Compressed files can be restored to their original form using gzip -d or gunzip or zcat.  If the original name saved in the compressed  file  is
       not suitable for its file system, a new name is constructed from the original one to make it legal.

       gunzip  takes  a list of files on its command line and replaces each file whose name ends with .gz, -gz, .z, -z, or _z (ignoring case) and which
       begins with the correct magic number with an uncompressed file without the original extension.  gunzip also recognizes  the  special  extensions
       .tgz  and  .taz as shorthands for .tar.gz and .tar.Z respectively.  When compressing, gzip uses the .tgz extension if necessary instead of trun‐
       cating a file with a .tar extension.

       gunzip can currently decompress files created by gzip, zip, compress, compress -H or pack.  The detection of  the  input  format  is  automatic.
       When  using the first two formats, gunzip checks a 32 bit CRC. For pack, gunzip checks the uncompressed length. The standard compress format was
       not designed to allow consistency checks. However gunzip is sometimes able to detect a bad .Z file. If you get an error when uncompressing a  .Z
       file, do not assume that the .Z file is correct simply because the standard uncompress does not complain. This generally means that the standard
       uncompress does not check its input, and happily generates garbage output.  The SCO compress -H format (lzh compression method) does not include
       a CRC but also allows some consistency checks.

       Files  created by zip can be uncompressed by gzip only if they have a single member compressed with the 'deflation' method. This feature is only
       intended to help conversion of tar.zip files to the tar.gz format.  To extract a zip file with a  single  member,  use  a  command  like  gunzip
       &lt;foo.zip or gunzip -S .zip foo.zip.  To extract zip files with several members, use unzip instead of gunzip.

       zcat is identical to gunzip -c.  (On some systems, zcat may be installed as gzcat to preserve the original link to compress.)  zcat uncompresses
       either a list of files on the command line or its standard input and writes the uncompressed data on  standard  output.   zcat  will  uncompress
       files that have the correct magic number whether they have a .gz suffix or not.

       Gzip uses the Lempel-Ziv algorithm used in zip and PKZIP.  The amount of compression obtained depends on the size of the input and the distribu‐
       tion of common substrings.  Typically, text such as source code or English is reduced by 60-70%.  Compression is generally much better than that
       achieved by LZW (as used in compress), Huffman coding (as used in pack), or adaptive Huffman coding (compact).

       Compression  is  always performed, even if the compressed file is slightly larger than the original. The worst case expansion is a few bytes for
       the gzip file header, plus 5 bytes every 32K block, or an expansion ratio of 0.015% for large files. Note that the actual number  of  used  disk
       blocks almost never increases.  gzip preserves the mode, ownership and timestamps of files when compressing or decompressing.

       The  gzip file format is specified in P. Deutsch, GZIP file format specification version 4.3, &lt;ftp://ftp.isi.edu/in-notes/rfc1952.txt&gt;, Internet
       RFC 1952 (May 1996).  The zip deflation format  is  specified  in  P.  Deutsch,  DEFLATE  Compressed  Data  Format  Specification  version  1.3,
       &lt;ftp://ftp.isi.edu/in-notes/rfc1951.txt&gt;, Internet RFC 1951 (May 1996).
         </description>
         <xeq>
            gzip
         </xeq>
         <help>
Usage: gzip [OPTION]... [FILE]...
Compress or uncompress FILEs (by default, compress FILES in-place).

Mandatory arguments to long options are mandatory for short options too.

  -a, --ascii       ascii text; convert end-of-line using local conventions
  -c, --stdout      write on standard output, keep original files unchanged
  -d, --decompress  decompress
  -f, --force       force overwrite of output file and compress links
  -h, --help        give this help
  -l, --list        list compressed file contents
  -L, --license     display software license
  -n, --no-name     do not save or restore the original name and time stamp
  -N, --name        save or restore the original name and time stamp
  -q, --quiet       suppress all warnings
  -r, --recursive   operate recursively on directories
  -S, --suffix=SUF  use suffix SUF on compressed files
  -t, --test        test compressed file integrity
  -v, --verbose     verbose mode
  -V, --version     display version number
  -1, --fast        compress faster
  -9, --best        compress better

With no FILE, or when FILE is -, read standard input.

Report bugs to &lt;bug-gzip@gnu.org&gt;.
         </help>
      </command>
   </commands>
</root>
